# **Derrick Adkins**

# Software Developer

(937) 903-1098 derrick.l.adkins@gmail.com Cincinnati, OH

#### **SUMMARY**

Marine Corps veteran with five years of experience in developing a variety of applications. Capable of quickly acquiring new skills. Proven ability to debug and optimize complex systems. Knowledgeable in unit testing and creating intuitive UI/UX.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Dart, Kotlin, Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, SQL

Software: Android Studio Electric Eel, GitHub Desktop,

VS Code, Arduino IDE

APIs & SDKs: Firebase, Flutter, Google Maps, Room DB, Retrofit, Operating Systems: Android, Windows, Linux

OkHttp, OAuth 2.0, Arduino, jQuery, Bootstrap

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# M2M Communications | Austin, Texas

**Software Developer** | September 2022 - April 2023

Kotlin

- Supplied quote for remote contract work.
- Analyzed existing system and developed plan to apply new requirements and features.
- Updated mobile RFID inventory application to support Android 11.
- Integrated modified API to RFID antenna.
- Facilitated publishing of application to Google Play Store.
- Communicated with project manager to ensure absolute satisfaction of completed work.

## Pelican Technologies | Dayton, Ohio

Senior Software Developer | October 2015 - October 2020

**Custom Software Solutions** 

Java | XML | SQLite | PHP

- Created RFID and barcode inventory management solutions for Android.
- Implemented Android features such as the camera, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, GPS, and user authentication.
- Built systems that synchronized inventory data from multiple client devices with a server-side database.
- Developed applications in the MVC structure.
- Designed responsive and intuitive interfaces.
- Used manufacturer's APIs to interface with RFID and barcode reading hardware.
- Utilized TCP connections to communicate between Windows and multiple Android RFID scanners simultaneously.

### Shumsky | Dayton, Ohio

Junior Applications Developer | May 2015 - September 2015

**Promotional Product Solutions** 

ColdFusion | JavaScript | SQL

- Used an internal ticketing system for maintaining internal web applications.
- Created web portal using existing database and infrastructure for accepting/rejecting images for the
- purpose of promotional products.
- Maintained legacy PICK/BASIC applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Cincinnati Graduated Spring 2024

Bachelor of Science in Software Development GPA: 3.9/4.0

**PROJECTS** 

adkinssalvage.com

Created a new website for Adkins Auto Salvage

Spring 2021

**Wellness Check** 

Created a new Android app for messaging Fall 2021

emergency contacts after a missed wellness check

**MASS Pre Job** 

Developed an Android app that leverages templates of a JotForm used for invoices Spring 2022

within MidAmerica Safety Solutions (MASS)

LocoQuest

Worked with a group to create a location-based game in which coins can be Spring 2023

collected

Phaser Tanks
Summer 2023

2D top-down tank combat game built using Phaser 3 game engine.

MASS Clock-In
Web app clock-in tool built for MidAmerica Safety Solutions (MASS)
Winter 2023

iFlow Capstone Project

Designed and built system to remotely monitor and control HVAC damper(s) Fall 2023 – Spring 2024